Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the Ten
Commandments that God had written for
the whole world to keep. Brother
Tynazael. And God spake all these words
saying, I am the Lord thy God, which
have brought thee out of the land of
Egypt, out of the house of bondage. Thou
shalt have no other gods before me.
Thou shalt not make unto thee any graven
image, or any likeness of anything that
is in heaven above, or that is in the
earth beneath, or that is in the water
under the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I the Lord thy God
am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity
of the fathers upon the children unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me, and showing mercy unto
thousands of them that love me, and keep
my commandments. Thou shalt not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain.
For the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that taketh his name in vain.
Remember the sabbath day, to keep it
holy.
Six days shalt thou labor, and do all
thy work.
But the seventh day
is the sabbath of the Lord thy God. In
it thou shalt not do any work,
thou, nor thy son, nor thy daughter, thy
manservant, nor thy maidservant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all that
in them is, and rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the sabbath
day, and hallowed it.
Honor thy father and thy mother, that
thy days may be long upon the land which
the Lord thy God giveth thee.
Thou shalt not kill. Thou shalt not
commit adultery. Thou shalt not steal.
Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shalt not
covet thy neighbor's house. Thou shalt
not covet thy neighbor's wife, nor his
manservant, nor his maidservant, nor his
ox, nor his ass, nor anything that is
thy neighbor's. We read Exodus 21
through 17. May the Lord have a blessing
to the reading of his words. In Jesus'
name we pray. Amen.
Amen.
Through real question and answer, you
can ask us a question and we'll answer
it according to the King James Bible.
And if we cannot find the answer, we
will seek further counsel to bring you
an answer at a later time.
The questions we will not answer are the
long scripture questions as well as the
vague questions and questions of debate.
We are not here to debate, we are here
to spread the true gospel of Jesus. So,
please be as direct as possible with
your questions so we can be as direct as
possible with our answers out of the
King James Bible. No other Bibles or
books will be acknowledged on this
program. Also, keep in mind that this is
a live stream, so feel free to send in
your questions that pertain to
everlasting life. We just ask that you
keep them to a two scripture maximum.
So, let me introduce you to family
that's on the panel this evening. We got
brother Jerome.
Grace and peace.
Brother Julius. Good evening, everybody.
Brother Dre.
Good evening.
Brother Tamzel.
Sister Deborah.
Good evening.
Brother Shawn.
And we have a guest caller with us and
I'm brother Cornell. Sister Deborah, let
us begin with our first question of the
evening.
Yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A.
A. Thomas says,
"In explaining
the timing of the day of Pentecost, the
reference in the Pentecost class was
to Jesus being in the grave Friday,
Saturday,
and Sunday.
Jesus was not in the grave on the first
day.
First day week. Uh
Leviticus 23:10-12
is given.
All right. So, this is dealing with the
Pentecost. Let's go to Leviticus
23:10-12,
and the guest caller will shed some
light from there.
Read it.
Speaking to the children of Israel, and
say unto them,
when you become into the land which I
give unto you, and shall reap the
harvest thereof, then you shall bring a
sheaf of the first fruit of your harvest
unto the priest.
And he shall wave the sheaf before the
Lord to be accepted for you.
On the morrow after the Sabbath, the
priest shall wave it.
And you shall offer that day when you
wave the sheaf
a male lamb without blemish of the first
year for burnt offering unto the Lord.
Now, you know, I don't know
what this person
uh uh
is saying,
but I know one thing,
in the year that Jesus died,
the uh uh uh uh
Passover uh uh
he went in the grave
that Wednesday night.
He was in there Thursday night and
Friday night.
And then, he was in there in the daytime
through the Friday and Saturday, and he
rose Saturday evening just before
sundown.
So, now, that year, when the first came,
he was not in the grave
on the first day of the week.
But, if he's talking about this last uh
Passover and Pentecost,
this time,
Passover started on Friday night.
So,
he was put in the grave Saturday night.
He was in there Sunday night and he was
in there Monday night.
And so and then he was in there
uh uh
Sunday uh uh
in in the daytime rather
uh Sunday in the daytime
Monday in the daytime and Tuesday in the
daytime. So now, you couldn't do the
wave sheaf offering
that's
first day of the week
this year
2025. So you had to go to the next first
day of the week because the wave sheaf
offering must be done on tomorrow after
Passover.
So a lot of people had the Passover, had
Pentecost a week
uh uh ahead of us is because they start
counting the first uh uh first day of
the week
after Jesus was in the grave.
But then
you have to wave you have to wave the
first fruit. That's what you get that of
your harvest. That mean he had to come
out of the ground. He didn't come out of
the ground to that Tuesday.
So now, I don't know what this person
meant.
But on the first year on the year that
he died, no, he was not in the grave on
the first day of the week. But this year
he was.
That's all I would say.
All right. We hope that answered your
question as we continue to move to our
next.
Moving on, Audrey Buck says, "If a
husband divorces his wife secretly then
remarries,
can the first wife remarry or is she
also committing adultery by moving on?"
And I have a similar
question from Daughter of Judah that
says
um
"If a man can divorce his wife and
remarry, Can the ex-wife remarry, too?
So, these are two similar questions
about remarrying after being divorced.
All right. I think what separates the
two is dealing with the word secretly
there.
Yes.
So, either way, whether it's secretly or
not secretly, guess caller.
Go to 1 Corinthians 7th chapter.
Read verses 13 and through 15.
1 Corinthians 7
Starting at verse 13.
Yeah.
And the woman which hath a husband that
believeth not,
and if he be pleased to dwell with her,
let her not leave him. For the
unbelieving husband is sanctified by the
wife, and the unbelieving wife is
sanctified by the husband. Else were
your children unclean, but now they are
holy.
But if the unbelieving believing depart,
let him depart. A brother or sister is
not under bondage in such cases, but God
hath called us to peace.
So, now, if the guy divorced the woman,
that means he's departed.
And if he going to divorce his wife,
that means he's not He's a non-believer.
Cuz if he were a believer, he wouldn't
wouldn't divorce her
if she had not gone out and committed
adultery on him.
So, if that's the case, then
if he give her a divorce, whether uh
knowingly or unknowingly, if he's the
one to do it, then that means that uh
he's departed.
And right here, according to what Paul
wrote, a sister is not under bondage.
Under bondage of what?
Of the marriage vow.
So, she go on about her life.
Don't have to say.
All right.
Hope that answers your question as we
continue to move on.
Moving on, Zando Football asks you to
explain Romans 13 verses 1 through 7. Is
this talking about the governments in
power?
All right.
Brother Julius, shed some light.
Let's look at this. See what the book
say about this. Yes, it's talking about
governments in power. Look how it
starts.
Tell them Romans 13 verse 1.
Let every soul be subject unto the
higher powers.
For there was no power but of God.
The powers that be are ordained of God.
This is talking about man, the
government of men which God establishes.
The The people that's in authority, your
presidents, your your your uh
your uh mayors, your
city council. All these people are in
power. Go ahead.
Whosoever therefore resist the power,
resist the ordinance of God. Uh-huh. And
they that resist shall receive to
themselves damnation. Go out there and
break the law and see what happens.
Continue.
For rulers are not a terror to good
works,
but to the evil. Think why? Because it
is evil to go against
uh those that the power that I
established. It must be justified, my
sisters and brothers, so you can have
peace in the land. Go ahead.
Wilt thou then not be afraid of the
power? Uh-huh. Do that which is good,
and thou shall have praise of the same.
The law say obey the laws of the land
for for uh for our sake and for the
Lord's sake. That's what he said.
Go ahead.
For he is the minister of God to thee
for good.
But if thou do that which is evil, be
afraid. Uh-huh.
For he beareth not the sword in vain.
Uh-huh. For he is the minister of God,
a revenger to execute wrath upon him
that doeth evil. That's why when COVID
was here, the government said shut down,
we had to shut down to keep people from
getting sick. Go ahead.
Wherefore ye must needs be subject, not
only for wrath, but also for conscience'
sake. Go ahead.
For for this cause pay you tribute also.
For they are God's ministers, attending
continually upon this very thing.
In other words, respect the the laws of
the land. As long as they don't conflict
with the word of God, you you respect
the laws of the land. Go ahead, one
more.
Render therefore to all their dues.
Tribute to whom tribute is due, custom
to whom custom, fear to whom fear, and
honor to whom honor. In other words, uh
when it's time, you pay your taxes, pay
your taxes.
You know, and when it's time to pay your
tithes, you pay your tithes.
So, it's about
uh operating up on the so that you can
have peace in the land.
That's all I got on that. Anybody want
to add?
All right. We'll leave it right there as
we continue to move on to our next
question.
Next question. Marcus Cambro says, "I
have a question about Habakkuk 2:2.
I heard Sunday Christians use this verse
many times, and they say that this means
that if you want something from God,
write it down. Is there any truth to
this verse being about that?"
All right, they want to go to that book
of Habakkuk, Micah, Nahum, and then
Habakkuk. And then, Brother Dre, what
about writing it down on a note,
brother?
Yeah, there's nothing wrong with writing
down something, but this is not what
this is saying right here.
This is
not a prescriptive
thing. This is descriptive. It's
describing what Habakkuk was told to do,
not for us to do it. So, it's not a
prescription for us,
but it's describing what Habakkuk was
told. So, pick it up in verse two. Go
ahead, brother.
This is Habakkuk two and two. Yep.
Habakkuk two and two.
And the Lord answered me and said,
"Write the vision and make it plain upon
tables, that he may run that readeth
it."
Mhm. So, Habakkuk was told to write the
vision
and make it plain that he may run that
readeth it. Go ahead.
For the vision is yet for an appointed
time.
But at the end it shall speak and not
lie.
Though it tarry, wait for it, because it
will surely come. It would not tarry.
Go ahead. But behold, his soul which is
lifted up is not upright in him.
But the just shall live by his faith.
So, the the the crux of it is that
a write the vision is for a time
appointed time and at the end it's going
to speak
and those that are just, they will live
by faith in the words that are spoken.
They going to trust in those words.
Right. Yeah. That's what this is talking
about. And I mean, in in Isaiah 30:8-9,
he says, "Write it in a book
that this is a rebellious people, people
that won't hear the law of the Lord."
This is what
Habakkuk was dealing with.
And Revelation,
you know, John was on the Isle of
Patmos.
Revelation 1:9-11
and was told what he sees, write it in
the book.
And so we can see that.
But let's go to one other place. Let's
go to Romans 1:16-17.
Romans 1:16-17.
That's it.
Go ahead when you get it, brother.
Romans 1:16.
Mhm.
For I am not ashamed of the gospel of
Christ.
For it is the power of God into
salvation to everyone that believe.
To the Jew first and also to the Greek.
Oh, you got to have faith. You got to
believe this. Go ahead.
For therein is the righteousness of God
revealed from faith to faith.
As it is written, the just shall live by
faith. That's what this is about, your
faith.
And walking in that faith. So, it's not
a it's not a prescription for us to
write down everything we see, although
writing something down if it come to you
is not a bad thing. That's all I got on
that.
I just wanted to I just wanted to make a
Just call. about
was written down with Habakkuk. The Lord
is telling him to write it down so we
can read it.
That is right.
Okay? I'm not the individual writing it
down.
That's
If he hadn't written
then we could not be reading it out,
could we? No, we could not.
He was addressing Habakkuk. Okay, that's
all I got to say. Yes, sir.
All right.
Hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next question.
Next question, daughter of Judah asks,
when Jesus returns,
will he rule for an additional 1,000
years before judgement day.
What will happen to us who are still
here on earth while he is ruling?
All right. So,
brother Jerome, what's going on when
Jesus returns and his rulership?
Okay, um
I'd like to answer
answer it in separated cuz it
seem like it's two questions there.
Um
But,
we have to drop that additional cuz it's
it's not going to be ruling like an
additional thousand years. You know,
when the Lord
return to this earth, he's going to rule
when he return on this earth
for a thousand years. And within that
thousand year
latter part of that thousand year reign
of Christ,
he going to have a judgement day.
Okay?
White throne judgement. And we read that
in that Revelations 20. So, let's go to
that Revelations 20.
And we're going to pick it up at verse 4
and we're going to skip.
When you get it, go ahead and read.
And I saw thrones and and they
sat upon them and judgement was given
unto them.
And I saw the souls of them that were
beheaded for the witness of Jesus
and for the word of God.
And which had not worshipped the beast,
neither his image, neither had received
his mark upon their forehead or in their
hands. They lived and reigned with
Christ a thousand years. So, when the
Lord
return to this earth, it's going to be a
first resurrection and those that are
worthy,
those in this fourth verse are worthy
and they're going to make the first
resurrection, and they're going to rule
and or reign with Christ a thousand
years
on this earth, all right? Now, during
the Lord's thousand-year reign, the
latter part of that thousand-year reign
of Christ, he's going to have a judgment
day. So, skip down to verse 11, read it
to the 12.
And I saw a great white throne, and him
that sat on it,
from whose face the earth and the
heavens fled away.
And there was found no place for them.
Mhm. And I saw the dead, small and
great, stand before God. And the books
were opened. And another book was
opened, which is the book of life.
And the dead were judged out of those
things which were written in the books
according to their works. They're going
to be judged according to their works.
The dead still before that white throne,
and Jesus is the one sitting on that
white throne.
And the saints that made that first
resurrection, they're going to be
judges, too.
Okay?
Read verse 14 and 15.
And death and hell were cast into the
lake of fire.
This is the second death.
And whosoever was not found written in
the book of life was cast into the lake
of fire.
Now, the reason why I'm reading those
two verses because he said death and
hell were cast into the lake of fire.
He's going to do away with death, all
right? So, after judgment day is over
with, there ain't going to be no more
death.
But he's going to do away with uh
this death
in the latter part of his thousand-year
reign,
during judgment day.
Okay? And he's going to throw death in
the lake of fire, and that's going to be
the end of it. No more Man ain't going
to be dying no more after this, okay?
So, now let's tie this with 1
Corinthians chapter 15.
And we're going to read verse 24 through
26.
1 Corinthians chapter 15
verse 24 through 26. When you get it, go
ahead and read.
Then cometh the end, when he shall have
delivered up the kingdom to God, even
the Father, when he shall have put down
all rule and all authority and power.
For he must reign till he have put all
enemies under his feet.
The last enemy that shall be destroyed
is death.
That's what he going to take care of
that during his thousand-year reign.
That last thing he going to take care of
is death. That's what we read in
Revelation where he say he death and
hell was cast into the lake of fire.
That's when he did it, okay? So, now
um devil, can you read that second
question?
Yes. What will happen to us who are
still here on Earth while he is ruling?
Okay, well,
you understand you going to have a
first resurrection. They going to meet
the Lord in the air, but they coming
back down to this Earth and they going
to rule with Christ. So, we we just read
that where he going to they going to
rule with Christ in Revelation, okay?
So, they going to be on this Earth, but
uh of course, you know the ones that
didn't make the first resurrection, but
weren't weren't killed,
they going to still be on this Earth,
okay? And what they going to be doing
while they
on this Earth, if he didn't kill them,
they going to be learning how to
uh uh serve
the Lord
and they going to be learning how to
keep his commandments, okay? But, let's
go read about uh those that make that
first resurrection
uh
when they meet the Lord in the clouds,
they going to reign with him a thousand
years.
Let's go they going to reign on this
Earth cuz they going to come back down,
okay? So, let's go to Revelation 5
and read verse 9 and 10.
When you get it, go ahead and read.
And they sung a new song saying, "Thou
are worthy to take the book and to open
the seals thereof.
For thou was slain and has redeemed us
to God by thy blood out of every kindred
and tongue and people and nation.
And has And has made us unto our God
kings and priests and we shall reign on
the earth." And them are the ones that's
going to reign with Christ for 1,000
years. He made them kings and priests
and they going to reign on the earth,
okay? Now,
let's go read about
uh what they going to uh the ones that
didn't make the first resurrection,
they're going to be learning how to
serve God and keep his commandments and
they're going to be on this earth doing
that, okay? So, one more place, let's go
to Isaiah the second chapter and read
verse two and three and that'll be it.
Isaiah 2, verse two and three. Go ahead
and get read when you get it. And it
shall come to pass in the last day that
the mountain of the Lord's house shall
be established in the top of the
mountains and shall be exalted above the
hills and all nations shall flow unto
it.
And many people shall go and say, "Come
ye, let us go up unto the mountain of
the Lord, to the house of the God of
Jacob and he will teach us his ways and
we will walk in his path. For out of
Zion shall go forth the law and the word
of the Lord from Jerusalem."
Yeah, these are flesh and blood people.
They didn't make the first resurrection,
but he didn't kill them. So, they're
going to say, "Well, well, we going to
go up. Let's get the word of the Lord."
And they're going to go to Jerusalem and
get that word. They're going to learn
how to serve God.
That's all I got on it.
All right.
Thank you for that, brother. All we got
to do is make that first resurrection
and we straight. Yeah.
All right.
As we move on to our next question.
Next one, she also says while studying
the Bible, how can you find the precept
answer that will back up the scripture
you are reading?
All right, brother Dre, when you
studying the Bible, how do you
set up these precepts that back up the
scriptures that you are reading?
The beautiful thing is that Israel of
God teaches by subject and title.
And if you come to the Israel of God
with your pen, notepad,
and patience,
your Bible,
and you take notes, you going to get
this word by subject and title. By the
time we get done
with the subject,
you got all the precepts lined up with
that particular subject. So, let's go to
Isaiah 28 and look at something here.
That's right. 28:9
Go ahead, brother.
Whom shall he teach knowledge? And whom
shall he make to understand doctrine?
Them that are weaned from the milk and
drawn from the breasts. So, the book
tells us in
1 Peter 2:2,
as newborn babies desire the sincere
milk of the word, and grow thereby.
So,
those that are weaned from the milk and
drawn from the breasts,
these are the ones that he's going to
teach knowledge and make to understand
doctrine. So, at the Israel of God, this
subject and title
thoroughly deals with those precepts.
So, you take notes,
and you study, and you speak on it, and
it's going to answer your questions, and
before you know it, after you talk for
so long, you digging in them notes,
them scriptures going to come to your
mind and then you
But go ahead, read a little more,
brother.
For precept must be upon precept.
Precept upon precept.
Line upon line, line upon line.
Here a little and there a little.
Mhm.
For with stammering lips and another
tongue will he speak to this people.
So this word is being spoken to us in
whatever language we find ourselves in.
Other tongues. Go ahead.
To whom he said, "This is the rest
wherewith you may cause the weary to
rest."
And this is the refreshing. Yet, they
would not hear.
Read the first part of that next verse.
But the word of the Lord was unto them
precept upon precept.
Precept upon precept.
That's it. So this is what you're
getting at the Israel of God. You
getting the word of God precept upon
precept, line upon line, subject and
title.
And it will teach you. Just have some
patience, continue to come and grow in
it.
Uh
you can read 2 Timothy 2 and 15, 1
Timothy
4 13, 15, and 16.
And it will encourage you to do the
same. I hope that helps.
Yes, sir. Cuz we we read out of all 66
books of the King James Bible, don't we,
Brother Dre?
All in the testament.
Yes, sir. All right.
Thank you for that. Hope that answered
their question as we move on to our
next.
Next one. Peggy ZLF asks, "Are there
foods that we are not supposed to eat on
Pentecost?"
And then she says, "What is it
unleavened
for the Sabbath yesterday?" I don't
understand that part.
All right. Let's see if Brother Julius,
can you uh
make some light out of this?
I'm still trying to figure that question
out, Cornell, but uh
the first part of that question is, "Are
there foods that we are not supposed to
eat on Pentecost?"
Nothing unclean.
Correct.
Okay?
Now, the second part of that was uh is
it unleavened
No, no, no. That Pentecost has nothing
to do with unleavened.
Unleavened is for the feast of
unleavened bread, which is we don't eat
nothing
with leaven in it for 7 days, but that's
not Pentecost.
All of the Lord's feast days,
except for the Day of Atonement, is what
when we fast, ought to be eaten with
unclean We We have to Our foods have to
be clean. Our diet Our diets for the
feasts, as well as our everyday life, is
supposed to be clean. Okay?
That's the best I can do with that
question. I don't know what she's saying
about unleavened for the Sabbath
yesterday. I don't understand that.
All right. So,
if you'd like to submit something and
clear it up a little bit, we'll
readdress it, but we hope that what our
brother gave you shed some light.
Let's move on to our next question,
sister.
Next question, Loving Mom asked, "Is it
against the dietary law
to have my placenta capsulated after
birth? It helps with postpartum
depression and other conditions. Is
there a scripture for this?
All right.
Guest caller.
11 chapter Leviticus tell you what you
supposed to eat.
That have nothing to do with the dietary
law.
All right. And we
And we definitely wish you the best with
that postpartum depression. It can be
tough on people.
All right. Right. We're going to move
on.
Could you guest caller repeat that? You
broke up. I don't care if Yeah. I I No,
I said all I'm going to say.
Leviticus 20 the 11 chapter tell you
what you can eat.
And and and what you And what you
talking about there? That don't have
nothing to do with the dietary law.
But you're not supposed to eat that
either.
All right. We're going to
move on to our next question.
Next question, daughter of Judah asked,
"What is Luke 23:54
referring to?"
Luke 23 and 54.
What is that talking about, brother
Jerome?
Let's Let's go read it.
You can get it go ahead.
And that day was the preparation of the
Sabbath drew on.
Mhm. It's saying that day was the
preparation
and the Sabbath drew on.
Um
The preparation in this case
is actually talking about the Passover,
the day of the Passover.
Okay? The Passover is the day before the
first day of the feast of unleavened
bread. And so, when you're making
preparation for the feast, the first day
of the feast of unleavened bread, it's
on the day of the Passover that you're
going to make that preparation, okay?
So, that's what the preparation day
actually is. It's It's the Passover.
Preparation for the first day of the
feast of unleavened bread, okay? So,
now, uh
let's go to
St. John, chapter 19, and read verse 31.
St. John 19:31.
Yeah.
Read.
The Jews, therefore, because it was the
preparation that the body should not
remain upon the cross on the Sabbath
day. Yes, cuz see,
he was on the cross on the Passover, and
the Passover fall on the 14th day on the
month Abib, okay? Now, the Sabbath that
drew on,
that's the feast The first day of the
feast of unleavened bread, which is on
the 15th day
of the month Abib, okay? So, pick it
back up at the top of that 31 and read
it all the way through.
The Jews, therefore, because it was the
preparation that the body should not
remain upon the cross on the Sabbath
day.
For that Sabbath day was a high day.
Besought Pilate that their legs might be
broken, and that they might be taken
away.
Yeah. So, that high Sabbath is the
feast of unleavened bread. That's the
high Sabbath mentioned in
uh verse that you put in the question.
That's all I got.
All right.
Okay, we hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
Next one. The Bayou Perspective asks,
"Was Job a Levite, or did Job come
before Levi? I am I'm asking because he
sacrificed animals to the Lord.
Brother Julius.
Job came before Levi.
He was not a Levi. You don't have to be
a Levi to sacrifice burnt offerings.
Go to Genesis chapter 8 10 0.
Job was around a long time before that.
Genesis chapter 8, read one verse, verse
20.
When you get it, go ahead. Genesis 8 and
And Noah built an altar unto the Lord
and took of every clean beast and of
every clean fowl and offered burnt
offerings on the altar.
And he did what?
And he offered
burnt offerings
on the altar. So, Noah was around
because
they came Levi and then came through
Shem, Noah's son Shem.
So, Levi wasn't even born yet. So,
therefore, you don't have to be a Levi a
Levi to offer the this was done before
that. Let's go to 1 Kings the 9th
chapter and this will be my last
scripture.
1 Kings chapter 9.
Remember the Levites were set up to
offer animal sacrifices. 1 Kings 9 and
pick it up and just uh verse 25 and
let's see who we talking about. 1 Kings
9 and verse 25. When you get it,
brother, go ahead and read it.
And three times in a year did Solomon
offer burnt offerings and peace
offerings upon the altar which he built
unto the Lord. Uh-huh. And he burnt
incense upon the altar that was before
the Lord.
So, he finished the house. Solomon was a
Jew.
David, his father. They came through the
lineage of Judah.
But, he offered sacrifices, but he
wasn't a Levite. So, this has nothing to
do with that.
That's all I got to say with that.
All right. Thank you for that.
Hope that answered their question as we
move on to our next one with a time
check.
Yes, the time is 8:07.
Eve Davies says, "When people say the 10
will get you in,
what about the dietary laws and all the
other statutes and laws?"
All right. Look like it's kind of like a
little two-part question here, but
we hear that term that the 10 will get
you in because we know that the the 10
Commandments are perfect.
And they help us all to be better
individuals when we walk in them, and
Brother Tenzel read those when we first
open up. You keep those Commandments,
you put yourself in a good place with
God.
But, as far as you asking about what
about the dietary laws and all other
statutes and laws, well, statutes and
laws can be interchangeable. Statute can
be a law, and a law can be a statute.
But, let's go into that Leviticus 11
chapter.
Leviticus
11.
And let's read it just a little bit
about the dietary law, and let's see who
gave it because this here will let you
know that it is still good
throughout the generations.
Leviticus 11, read 1 and 2, and then we
going to skip down. Go ahead, brother.
And the Lord spake unto Moses and to
Aaron, saying unto them, "Speak unto the
children of Israel, saying, These are
the beasts which you shall eat among all
the beasts that are on the earth.
But this is the Lord speaking to Moses
saying, "Out of
all the beasts I created, these are the
beasts which you shall eat." And he also
talks about the ones that you shall not
eat. Skip down, brother, and pick it up
at verse uh
43.
Go ahead.
Ye shall not make
yourselves abominable with any creeping
thing that creepeth. Neither shall ye
make yourself unclean with them, that ye
should be defiled thereby.
For I am the Lord your God. Ye shall
therefore sanctify yourselves, and ye
shall be whole, for I am holy. Neither
shall ye defile yourself with any manner
of creeping thing that creepeth upon the
earth.
So, the things that the Lord say you
shall not eat, he don't want you to
defile yourself with that. Why? Go
ahead, brother.
For I am the Lord that bringeth you up
out of the land of Egypt to be your God.
Ye shall therefore be whole,
for I am holy.
So, when you asked us about the word law
and statutes, here go a law right here,
and it should be a statute
throughout generations. Go ahead, 46,
brother.
This is the law of the beasts and of the
fowl,
and of every living creature that moveth
in the water, and of every creature that
creepeth upon the earth.
To make a difference between the unclean
and the clean, and between the beast
that may be eaten
and the beast that may not be eaten.
So, the Lord is putting a separation
here.
Behind the beasts that you can eat and
the ones he do not want you to eat
because you can make yourself abominable
by eating those things. So, this dietary
law can easily be followed by the God
who created us all. But let's go into um
cuz I know you talked about statutes and
laws as well. Let's go into Acts 8 right
quick. Acts 8.
Because one of the things that's missing
from people's lives as far as the
statutes and laws is right here in this
Acts 8 with some people. Acts 8 and pick
it up there verse 26 when you get there,
brother. Go ahead.
And the angel of the Lord speaking to
Philip saying, "Arise and go towards the
south unto the way that goeth down from
Jerusalem and Gaza, which is desert."
And he arose and went. And behold, a man
of Ethiopia, a eunuch of great authority
under Candace, queen of the Ethiopians,
who had the charge of all her treasures
and had come to Jerusalem for to
worship. So we had Ethiopia, who was who
had a good position. And Philip was sent
down there because he was reading the
book. But like brother Dre say, "Hey,
you got to have somebody to be able to
give you this word in its pure form." Go
ahead.
Was returning and sitting in his chariot
reading Isaiah the prophet. Mhm. And the
spirit said unto Philip, "Go near and
join thyself to this chariot."
And Philip ran thither to him and heard
him read the prophet Isaiah and said,
"Understandest thou what thou readest?"
So he was reading the book and then
Philip said, "Hey, do you understand
what you're reading?" And what did the
guy say?
And he said, "Well, how can I except
some man should guide me?"
Uh-huh. And he desired Philip that he
would come up and sit with him.
Now, in that verse it lets you know that
everybody doesn't qualify to guide
somebody, but this is
what makes you qualified. Let's go into
uh Proverbs 12.
Proverbs 12.
Ecclesiastes 12. I'm sorry, brother.
Ecclesiastes 12. Let's go there and read
that.
Because this is what Philip was bringing
to the table for that guy who said, "How
can I learn except some guy should guide
me?" This is how you This is who you
have to have teaching you. Verse 9, go
ahead.
And moreover, because the preacher was
wise, he still taught the people
knowledge.
Yeah, he gave good heed and sought out
and set in order many proverbs. And
that's what Philip was giving that
Ethiopian. He was giving him that
knowledge, that word of God. Go ahead.
The preacher sought to find out
acceptable words, and that which was
written was upright, even words of
truth. Words of truth cuz lies cannot
profit you. Go ahead.
The words of the wise are as goads and
as
nails fastened by the masters of
assemblies,
which are given from one shepherd. And
given from one shepherd, because when
it's given from one shepherd, and you
got the prophets, you got the apostles,
and you got everybody else
bringing forth this same word that was
given from one shepherd, which is Jesus
who created us all. And that's all I
got. Anybody else want to add?
Yeah.
Go ahead, guest caller. Guest caller?
Read.
What was the question? Reread it.
Yes, the question was when people say
the 10 will get you in, what about the
dietary laws and all the other statutes
and laws?
I'm going to give you the perfect
example. Go to Isaiah the 66th chapter,
read verses 15 and 16. Yes, sir.
Isaiah 66, verse 15.
For behold, the Lord will come with
fire,
and with his chariots like a whirlwind,
to render his anger with fury and his
rebuke with flames of fire.
For by fire and by sword will the Lord
plead with all flesh.
And the slain of the Lord shall be many.
And they that sanctify themselves and
purify themselves in the garden
behind one tree in the midst, eating
swine flesh,
and the abomination and the mouse shall
be consumed together, saith the Lord.
Well, that's not a part of the team, is
it?
Mhm. No.
If there's anything the Lord command you
to do,
you do it.
Or you end up just like we just read.
I think that's clear.
Yeah.
So, don't say.
Like you said, weren't a part of the
team, but
somebody who understood the scriptures
had to bring that forward to help them
to understand.
All right.
We hope that answered your question,
ma'am, as we move on to our next one.
Next one. Christmas is pagan as when
should you
when should we start the Sabbath? I
usually look at the time on the weather
app that says when the sun sets,
but I've been hearing that we should
wait until there's no light outside.
Can you please provide some clarity?
All right, we're going to open this up
to the panel, but yeah, you are hearing
correctly that when it's dark out
because just cuz the sun set, it doesn't
mean that the west is not still well lit
up that you can see.
So, open to the panel, when should they
start?
Why don't we read one thing?
Go in the Proverbs the 7th chapter and
read verse 9.
Proverbs 7
and verse
9.
That's that twilight piece. In the
twilight,
in the evening, in the black and dark
night.
That is when the day start.
When it is dark.
Simple.
Okay?
Yep, and that don't start at sunset.
It's when it's dark.
When it's dark, when it's dark.
Read the verse one more time.
In the twilight,
in the evening,
in the black and dark night.
That's clear, isn't it?
Crystal.
All right.
Hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next question.
Next one. Be low pass asked, "What is a
prophet and an apostle?
Do we still have prophets and apostles
today?"
What is a prophet and apostle and do
they still exist today? Yes, caller.
Prophet is one that brings the message
of God.
They get it directly from
God angel.
And he brings the message to man.
The apostles
is one that teaches the word.
Who, you know, even though prophets
teach too, but the prophet is the one
that deliver the message, but the
apostles is the one that teaches the
message
from God.
That's all I have to say.
All right. Well, hope that answered your
question. And as sister Deborah, we
We're into new territory?
Yes, we are. So, we are now into
tonight's Q&A for Wednesday, June the
18th,
2025.
Sister Tanisha asked you to explain 1
Corinthians 7:18-20
and Colossians 2:11.
All right.
Why don't we open these questions up to
the panel, but let's start off first,
Candace, with that 1 Corinthians 7.
Read that 18-20,
and we'll open that up to the panel.
Is any man called being circumcised? Let
him not become uncircumcised.
Is any called in uncircumcision?
Let him not be circumcised.
Circumcision is nothing, and
uncircumcision is nothing.
But, the keeping of the commandments of
God.
Let Let every man abide in the same
calling wherein he was called.
Open to the panel.
Hello, K-Dawg. Now, Paul wrote that,
right?
If a man is called uncircumcised, don't
let him become circumcised. Let's get Go
and see what God said about that.
I think it's Genesis Let's see. Is it
Genesis the uh
Ooh, let me see.
Because Peter told us one thing, we have
a more sure word of prophecy.
So, we're going back to the prophets and
to the law.
When God made the covenant.
Genesis 17.
We're going to go and see what the Lord
said here.
Genesis chapter 17.
Because uh
In fact, while I'm looking for this, I
want some go and find I want somebody to
go and read what Peter said. I think it
was in 1 Peter.
I want you to go read that first.
What Peter said what Peter said he have
not followed cunning fables.
And
we have a more sure word of prophecy.
Oh, that's
1 Peter 9. 2 Peter 1
and 16.
What is it
1 Peter? 2 Peter 1 and 16.
Is it okay? I'll just start out.
Uh for we have not followed cunningly
devised fables.
Okay, read it. unto you the power and
coming of our Lord Jesus Christ.
But we
saw of his majesty.
For he received from God the Father
honor and glory
when there came such a voice to him from
the excellent glory. This is my beloved
son in whom I am well pleased. And this
voice which came from heaven we heard
when we were with him in the holy mount.
But we have also a more sure word of
prophecy.
Whereunto you do well that you take heed
as unto a light that shineth in the dark
place until the day dawn and the day
star arise in your heart. But knowing
this first
that no prophecy of the scripture is of
any private interpretation.
For the prophecy came not in old time by
the will of man, but holy men of God
spake
as they were moved by the Holy Ghost.
Okay, now. So, we said that we have a
more sure word of prophecy. Is that what
Peter said? That's what we read.
He's the guy that Jesus left the keys of
the kingdom with. Isn't that correct?
Yes, sir.
We're going to listen to him. So, let's
go back to prophecy. Go to Genesis, the
17th chapter.
And we're going to start reading at
verse 9. We're going to read a little
bit.
And God said unto Abraham,
"Thou shalt keep my covenant, therefore
thou and thy seed after thee in their
generations.
This is my covenant, which you shall
keep between me and you and thy seed
after thee. Every man child among you
shall be circumcised.
And you shall circumcise the flesh of
your foreskin, and it shall be a token
of the covenant betwixt me and you.
And he that is eight days old shall be
circumcised among you.
Every man child in your generation,
he that is born in the house or bought
with money of any stranger, which is not
of thy seed.
But he that is born in thy house
Look, that is that is that covers
everybody, don't it? Everybody.
Everybody that's born in the house and
the stranger
that's bought with money. That means if
you bought him, he's a part of the
household.
So, if you're going to be a you know, so
uh uh uh uh
you got to make sure So, that we're
going to show you that that that money
represent Jesus' blood. But go ahead and
read.
He that is born in thy house, and he
that is bought with that money
must needs be circumcised. And my
covenant shall be in your flesh for an
everlasting covenant.
Now, look. Look, who's talking here?
Who's talking?
This is the Lord talking.
There you go.
And he used two strong words, which are
absolute, didn't he? Absolute.
Must need be circumcised. Now, let's see
what happen if you're not. Go ahead.
And the uncircumcised man child whose
flesh of his foreskin is not
circumcised, that soul shall be cut off
from his people. He hath broken my
covenant.
Now, can God lie?
No, sir.
Impossible.
Keep reading.
And God said unto Abraham, "As for Sarai
thy wife, thou shalt not call her name
Sarai, but Sarah shall be shall her name
be.
And I will bless her
and give thee a son also of her. Yea, I
will bless her and she shall be a mother
of nations, kings of people shall be of
her."
Okay, so you got to be circumcised,
right? What verse is that?
That was in the 16th.
Okay, now, Abraham was Abraham
circumcised when God brought that to
him? Nope. That's right.
Now, according to what we read in
Corinthians, he wasn't you know, he was
the Lord found him when he was in his
uncircumcision, didn't he? Yes.
So, if you find the Lord when you're
uncircumcised according to what we just
read in 1 Corinthians 15th chapter, you
ain't supposed to get circumcised. Isn't
that correct?
Is that what it read?
That's what it said.
No, you must needs be circumcised.
No, I'm talking about what 1 Corinthians
said.
Yes, sir.
That's what it
Read it again.
Cuz I'm cuz cuz I cuz I'm particular
about this. Go read it again what it
said about people find in uncircumcised.
But keep your finger here, we're coming
back here.
That was 1 Corinthians 7:10 through 18
to 20?
Is any man called
Yep.
Is any man called being circumcised? Let
him not become uncircumcised.
Is any called in uncircumcision?
Let him not be circumcised.
Circumcision is nothing and
uncircumcision is nothing, but the
keeping of the commandments of God.
Let every man abide in the same calling
wherein he was called.
So, according to this, Abraham shouldn't
have got circumcised. Isn't that Isn't
that correct? Right.
Now, let's go back to Genesis 17th
chapter
and read verses
24.
And he left off talking
to 25. Go ahead and to 26, rather. 22 to
26. Read it.
And he left off talking with him, and
God went up from Abraham.
And Abraham went up from him.
God went up from Abraham, not Moses,
right? Right.
Go ahead.
And Abraham took Ishmael, his son, and
all that were born in his house, and all
that were bought with his money, every
male among the men of Abraham's house,
and circumcised the flesh of their
foreskin in the selfsame day as God had
said unto him.
Go ahead.
And Abraham was 90 years old and nine
when he was circumcised in the flesh of
his foreskin.
And Ishmael
his son was 13 years old when he was
circumcised in the flesh of his
foreskin.
And the selfsame day was Abraham
circumcised and Ishmael, his son.
And all the men of the house born in the
house and bought with money of the
stranger were circumcised with him.
So, Abraham he didn't listen to what was
written in 1 Corinthians, was it?
See, he didn't listen.
More sure word of prophecy.
That's right. Now, let's go to let's go
to Galatians the 3rd chapter and see
what Paul said.
Maybe he should have listened to
himself. First Corinthians, I'm not
first Corinthians, Galatians the 3rd
chapter.
Because it's t- It's it's time out.
for New Testament Christianity by
itself. That's why the Lord said the law
and the testimony.
If you don't teach according to this,
there ain't no light in you.
Now we're going to start at at verse 26.
We're going to read down to 29. You can
start when you get there.
For ye are all the children of God by
faith in Christ Jesus.
For as many of you as have been baptized
into Christ have put on Christ.
There is neither Jew nor Greek, there is
neither bond nor free, there is neither
male nor female, for ye are all one
in Christ Jesus.
And if you be Christ,
then are you Abraham's seed and heirs
according to the promise.
Do not if you are Abraham's seed and you
are a male, what must you be?
Circumcised.
End of story.
Go to the next one.
All right. And uh sister Deborah, what
was that next scripture?
Colossians 2:11.
Please explain.
Read that and we'll keep that open till
the time is well. That Colossians 2:11
Yep.
Yes.
In that room also do you are circumcised
with the circumcision made without
hands.
And putting off the body of the sins of
the flesh by the circumcision of Christ.
All right.
Look.
That's it, right?
Yep.
Oh.
Who was the first one that said
circumcise the foreskin of your
of your heart? Can somebody go and find
that? I think it's in Deuteronomy the
30th chapter. I ain't sure.
All right. Let me search more for that.
Should be coming up with that
shortly.
Uh Deuteronomy 10
and 16.
Yes. Yeah.
Call the person read it.
Say it again. Do What was you guys at?
Deuteronomy 10 and 16.
Okay. Deuteronomy 10:16.
It is kind of in
uh Deuteronomy 30 and 6. Deuteronomy 10
and 16.
Circumcise therefore the foreskin of
your heart and be no more stiff-necked.
Now Moses told you that, didn't he?
Mhm. Do not circumcise the foreskin of
your heart and don't be stiff-necked.
That means you're going to obey God.
Isn't that correct? That's right. That's
right.
You've always had to have a
a circumcision of the mind.
Always. Or you wouldn't walk in the
word.
Period.
It's all that simple.
So it's again, since we mentioned this,
circumcision of This was Paul. He was
making the argument, but he wasn't
talking about Israel.
He was talking about
stranger.
Let's go into Acts.
Where is that? Acts 15.
I think it's Acts 15.
And we're going to start in
I'll read that verse one.
Yep.
Read it when you get there.
And certain men which came down from
Judea taught the brethren and said,
"Except you be circumcised after the
manner of Moses, you cannot be saved."
So when therefore Paul and Barnabas
Go ahead.
So when therefore Paul and Barnabas had
no small dissensions and this
disputation with them,
they determined that Paul and Barnabas
and certain others of them should go up
to Jerusalem unto the apostles and
elders about this question.
Uh-huh. What question?
brought Go ahead.
And being brought on their way by the
church, they passed through Phoenicia
and Samaria declaring the conversation
of the Gentiles. Conversion.
Conversion
of the Gentiles, and they caused great
joy unto all the brethren.
And And when they were come to
Jerusalem, they were received of the
church and of the apostles and elders.
And they declared all things that God
had done with them.
Uh-huh.
But there arose up certain of the sects
of the Pharisees which believed, saying,
that it was needful to circumcise them,
and to command them to keep the law of
Moses.
And who was them he was talking about?
The strangers, Gentiles.
There you go. Gentiles, which is a
stranger.
And they went through all of it. I'm
just cuz I'm just saying I'm just
showing you something that the whole
world is overlooking.
This conversation and this argument was
Paul with the apostles and the other
Israelites uh Pharisees that had
converted concerning the Gentiles.
Never included Israel. Go go to 16th
chapter and read verse one.
16 and one.
Then came he to Derby and Lystra, and
behold, a certain disciple was there,
named Timotheus,
the son of a certain woman, which was a
Jewess, and believed, but his father was
a Greek.
Which was well reported of by the
brethren that were at Lystra and
Iconium.
Him would Paul have to go forth with
him,
and took the and took and circumcised
him because of the Jews which were in
those quarters. For they knew all that
his father was a Greek.
Still, he had a Hebrew mother.
Right.
So he took him and circumcised cuz I'm
making a point here.
Now let's look let's uh uh uh
now let's look and show you what the uh
uh uh
get down to verse
24 cuz they saying that the Paul them
was has been preaching that Jews
shouldn't be circumcised.
Let's see it see uh
Let's see.
The more as much as we heard
Mhm.
Go to somewhere where where where Paul
and them where they where they started
to they had to
they had a accused Paul
of saying that the Jews shouldn't be
circumcised. Acts 20
Acts 20 and 21
Yeah, okay.
Acts 21 Acts 21 and 20
one
Acts 21 and 21
Okay.
I start reading it there.
And they and they are informed of thee
that thou teaches all the Jews which are
among the Gentiles to forsake Moses
saying that they ought not to circumcise
their children neither to walk after the
custom.
They not Now this is what's going on
nowadays. Now you got Israelites saying
you ain't got to be circumcised.
Right.
Nobody. But but Paul was they falsely
accused him here though concerning the
Jews. But but now he said but we know
better. Skip down
Keep just keep reading.
What is it therefore? The multitude must
needs come together for they would they
will hear that thou art come.
Do therefore
Do therefore this that we say to thee
we have four men which have a vow on
them.
So them take and purify thyself with
them and be at charges with them that
they may shave their heads and all may
know that those things whereof they were
informed concerning thee are nothing but
that thou thyself also walkest orderly
and keepest the law.
Now this is the so they
now they say, "Look, we know that you
were doing that you ain't teaching this,
that you walking and you keeping the
law."
This concerning you, the Israelite, but
then read the next verse.
As touching the Gentiles which believe,
we have written and concluded that they
observe no such thing,
save only that they keep themselves from
things offered to idols and from blood
and from strangled and from fornication.
So in other words, Peter is telling
Luke, "But we But we said that the
Gentiles That's after the argument in
Acts 15 chapter. They wrote a letter
that okay, then the Gentiles won't have
to be circumcised.
But that don't coincide with prophecy,
do it?" No, it does not.
God It wasn't no Jew, wasn't no
Israelite when God gave it to Abraham.
And Abraham
is His name was Abram, but God made him
the father of many nations.
He's the even the father of the
faithful. Therefore, his name was
changed to Abraham.
But the thing about it, the argument was
never about Israelites being
circumcised.
That was a foregone conclusion. The
argument came which which Paul reads
about Gentiles being circumcised.
So the world don't know that. Now you
got people running around saying don't
nobody have to be circumcised. You only
be circumcised in the mind. Go to this
Bible and find out. The only one that uh
Peter and Paul them let off the hook was
the Gentiles.
But according to the word of God,
according to prophecy, every male
supposed to be circumcised, whether he's
an Israelite
or whether he's a stranger. And that's
all I have to say about that.
So if any man that want to go around and
Paul, right? I hope you hear me. So,
you have been told.
And the Lord said
to Ezekiel,
"I make you a watchman.
Warn the people about me."
That's all I have to say.
All right.
And I say
Yeah.
Ezequiel 44.
Right.
Go ahead.
Ezequiel 44.
And pick it up
six and read it to nine.
Thou shall say unto the rebellious, even
to the house of Israel, "Thus saith the
Lord God, all ye house of Israel, let it
suffice you of all your abomination.
And that ye have brought into my
sanctuary strangers uncircumcised in
heart and uncircumcised in flesh to be
in my sanctuary to pollute it even my
house.
When you offer my bread, the fat and the
blood,
and that have broken my covenant because
of all your abomination.
And ye have not kept my kept the charge
of my holy things,
but ye have set keepers of my charge in
my sanctuaries for yourselves.
Thus saith the Lord God, "No stranger
uncircumcised in heart nor uncircumcised
flesh
shall enter into my sanctuary of any
stranger
that is among the children of Israel."
That is right. So,
this is letting you know you have to be
circumcised in heart and in flesh. And
this is
for a time to come. That's right.
Mhm.
Yeah. That's right. Cuz
we know all the women have to be
circumcised too in the mind. That's
right.
And the men that's in the truth
confuse it with the issue. We ain't
going to confuse them with the issue.
We're going to get with the males.
Okay. What's the orders of the
circumcision?
I mean it's the order of the Passover.
All right, I want to read two more
places cuz I want to kill this.
Order of the That's in That's in Exodus
the 12th chapter. Yes, sir.
And uh
What, 43? Mhm.
Okay.
Go on reading.
And the Lord said unto Moses and Aaron,
"This is the orders of the Passover.
There shall no stranger eat thereof.
But every man servant that is bought for
money, when thou has circumcised him,
then shall he eat thereof.
A foreigner and a hired servant shall
not eat thereof.
Go ahead.
In one house shall it be eaten. Thou
shall not carry forth out of the flesh
abroad out of the house, neither shall
ye break a bone thereof.
All the congregation of Israel shall
keep it.
And when a stranger shall sojourn with
thee and will keep the Passover to the
Lord, let all his males be circumcised,
and then let him come near and keep it.
And he shall be as one that is born in
the land.
For no uncircumcised person shall eat
thereof.
So he said a stranger, if you're going
to keep the Passover, then you got to
get circumcised. You're going to be like
one born in the land. He said it should
be from one law for all. Isn't that
correct? Yes, sir. Mhm. That's right.
Passover.
Now, let's see who the Passover is.
First Corinthians, I think it's 5 and 7.
Yes, sir.
Read it when you get there.
First Corinthians 5
Purge out therefore the old leaven
that ye may be a new lump,
as ye are unleavened.
For even
Christ our passover is sacrificed for
us.
So, Christ is the passover, ain't that
what we just read? Right.
So now, can you take part in Christ if
you're not circumcised? Nope.
Point me.
What do I have to say?
All right. Well, hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next.
Moving on. Say Amaroo Israel asks, "What
does Jesus mean by let the dead bury the
dead? Luke 9:60,
Matthew 8:22
is given.
Is this saying to avoid funerals or
comfort loved ones during bereavement?"
All right. Two different questions here.
Let's go to that Luke 9 first. We'll
open this up to the panel, too. Cuz we
know he's talking about the spiritually
dead, but let's go and read that Luke 9.
When you get there, brother.
And then we're going to read that
Matthew's right after cuz both of them
are saying the same thing.
Luke 9, let's pick it up. Read 59 and
60.
And he said unto another, "Follow me."
But he said, "Lord, suffer me first to
go and bury my father."
And Jesus said unto him,
"Let the dead bury their dead.
But go thou and preach the kingdom of
God." All right. Now, go to that Matthew
8 and read that 21 and 22.
And another of his disciples said unto
him, Lord, suffer me first to go and
bury my father. And Jesus said unto him,
Follow me,
and let the dead bury their dead.
All right. Now, let's open it up to the
panel.
No, he's
he's talking about two different types
of uh
dead, you know, you got the dead where
you ain't breathing, but you got a dead
where you breathing, we like to call it
dead men walking.
Okay? They don't have no spiritual
understanding, they don't have the word
of God, they being led by things that
bring forth death. If they continue they
in, they going to die the second death,
too, okay? But the best verse to explain
what it really talking about is Hosea
the 13th chapter.
And we read verse 1 and 2.
You know, but let's go to the one that
you get you you read the ones that they
gave already, so let's go to Hosea 13.
Read verse 1 and 2.
When Ephraim spake trembling, he exalted
himself in Israel.
But when he offended in Baal, he died.
Baal Baal is a pagan god, so if you
dealing with paganism,
you you spiritually dead, okay?
Even though you still walking around
here breathing and living physically,
okay? Keep reading.
And now they sin more and more, But they
dead while how they continuing to sin if
they dead physically?
That's because you not talking about
physical That's why he said, "Let the
dead" spiritually dead, that's dealing
with all types of paganism, let them
bury the physical dead. Right. Go ahead
and finish that.
And now they sin more and more, and have
made them molten image of their silver,
and idols according to their own
understanding.
All of it, the work of the craftsman.
And they say to of them, let the man
that sacrifice kiss the calf. And that's
it. That's all I got.
Yeah. And so,
he's just merely saying, "Hey,
let the spiritually dead bury their
dead. You come and follow me. I am
preaching life here."
So,
Sister Deborah, the last part of that is
also what?
That is he just put in his
interpretation of what it meant. He
says, "Does this mean to avoid funerals
or comfort loved ones during
bereavement?" So, you told him what it
is, the spiritual dead
bury the physical dead. That is what he
meant by let the dead bury the dead.
Right. And it And it doesn't mean that
you have to avoid funerals based on what
is read. And if someone is grieving
behind their loved one, it doesn't mean
that you can't comfort comfort them
during the time of their loss as well.
And Brother Drake,
Yeah. Um on your own, you can read
Ephesians 2.
He let you know you had the quicken
who was dead in trespasses and sin.
So,
he he made you alive who were
spiritually dead.
And and which we all had our times where
we walked that way.
But God who is rich in mercy,
even when we were dead in sins, has
quickened us
with Christ.
So,
the thing is this dead again is talking
about the spiritually dead burying the
physically dead.
Plus again, too,
he was telling it to this guy who the
guy
that he was choosing to be an apostle.
Right.
Okay?
Yes, sir.
Everybody, he was saying to that
particular guy that that he said,
"Follow me." He was picking to be one of
his apostles.
That's right.
Do you still
You still go to funerals or your family
going to hate you? And then they going
to hate your God because they going to
send you in a cult that's saying that
because you're true God, you can't go to
no funeral or or go to your friend your
That's right.
Don't make Don't make the truth into a
cult.
That's it.
That's all I got to say.
Feel free to comfort somebody who may
have lost their loved one.
That's not against the rules, either.
Okay?
All right. Well, hopefully that answered
your question, Sister Deborah. Time
check as we move on to our next one. And
these also will be open to the panel.
Okay, the time is 8:50. Next one, Cassio
Lee says, "I have a son, 35,
who follows, watches different
personalities on YouTube that talks
about consciousness, the universe, and
energy.
Can you please give me some scripture to
show him where going where giving power
to the universe and
energy is against God?"
All right. Um
open to the panel.
Sound like he kind of following some
things that do not pertain to the book.
You know, zodiacs and things of that
nature also is a part of some of the
things that people follow and that's a
no-no. Open to the path.
Go Revelation 20 chapter
and go to the judgment.
Start with the books is over.
Verse 12.
Verse
Go ahead.
And I saw the dead small and great stand
before God, and the books were opened,
and another book was opened, which is
the book of life. And the dead were
judged out of those things which were
written in the books according to their
works.
The dead The dead were judged out of
those things which what?
Which were written in the books.
Talking about the Bible here.
If it's not written in the Bible,
then you got a problem. Just like going
taking a test
and you don't and you haven't gotten the
the you haven't read the book that the
test is is based on.
And you're going to all of these books
and everything else, uh-uh.
You're going to be judged by the things
that are written in
this book, the Bible, according to your
works.
Right.
I have to say.
Yeah.
All right.
Moving on to our next question.
Next question. Britt Brett says, "Jesus
Christ cast out seven devils out of Mary
Magdalene.
Were they around her or inside of her?"
Mark 16:9
is given. And her other question is,
"Are the fallen angels who follow Satan
called demons or devils or both?"
They're called
demons, devils,
familiar spirits.
Yeah, but uh let's go to that uh
Mark 16
and let's deal with that verse uh
nine
and again, she was talking about the
devils, the seven devils that was in
Mary Magdalene. And her question to that
was what, Deborah?
Were they around her or inside of her?
Matthew 6 Mark 16:9. I'm sorry, go
ahead, Tenzel, and open it to the pan.
Now when Jesus was risen early the first
day of the week he appeared first to
Mary Magdalene
out of whom he had cast seven devils.
Now go to
Now somebody can find this where
when they was having the pastor with and
and uh
and the Lord
and Judas and and the two and the Lord
told Judas to do what he had to do.
Oh, he was saying and Satan
uh uh put into Judas' mind. You got that
twice. One said he put into his mind and
one said that uh uh
he went into him.
Um John Saint John
13th chapter verse two.
Read it. See what it say.
And supper being ended, the devil having
now put into the heart of Judas
Iscariot, Simon's son, to betray him.
Okay. Now it said put into his heart,
didn't it?
Right.
And he put into his mind, but there was
another one the same thing it reads
another way. So you can get a better a
concept of it.
See if you can find that.
All right. Let me search more for that.
I know one we got in Acts the 5th
chapter with Ananias and Sapphira.
No, no, there's another about Judas
here.
What What was that one you just read?
Let me see if I can find it. What was
the first one? It was in what?
I think it's Luke. It might be Luke
22:3.
Read it. What does it say?
Then entered Satan into Judas, surnamed
Iscariot,
being of the number of the 12.
Okay, yes, that's right. Then entered
him, okay? Right.
we read it
said he put it in his mind in his heart,
didn't
In his heart, right.
So, the the devils wasn't inside of her,
the devils was inside of her mind. They
was influencing her.
Just like it was with Judas.
Devil was not inside.
He influenced
Judas.
Like the seven devils was not inside of
the woman, they influenced her.
Just like Satan
influenced Eve.
Simple as that.
Information.
What you say?
Like the devil influenced Eve through
conversation and persuaded her.
Yeah, you don't.
In fact, go to Genesis.
3rd chapter.
Start at one.
Three and one.
Now, the serpent was more subtle than
any beast of the field
which the Lord God had made. And he said
unto the woman,
"Yea, have God said, 'Ye shall not eat
of every tree of the garden?'"
And the woman said unto the serpent, "We
may eat of the fruit of the trees of the
garden,
but of the fruit of the trees which is
in the midst of the garden, God hath
said, 'Ye shall not eat of it. Neither
shall ye touch it, lest ye die.'"
And the serpent said unto the woman, "Ye
shall not surely die.
For God doth know that in the day ye eat
thereof, then your eyes shall be opened,
and ye shall be as gods, knowing good
and evil."
So, so Eve liked that. You understand?
"I'm going to be as God." But, keep
reading.
And when the woman saw that the tree was
good for food, and that it was pleasant
to the eyes, and a tree to be desired to
make one wise,
she took of the fruit thereof, and did
eat,
and gave also unto her husband with her,
and he did eat.
Now, so the whole thing is, Satan didn't
go inside of Eve, but he influenced her.
Right.
He saw that this this fruit is good for
knowledge and stuff like that, and and
and and and pleasant to the sight. I
like it.
So, she was influenced. So, she he went
into her he went into her mind by
influencing her. Like in the new book,
it said, "Adam was not deceived. Eve
was."
So, if a devil could go inside of you
and make you sin against God,
and uh uh uh you couldn't do nothing
about it,
then how can he judge you? How could God
judge you? No, just like it was with
Judas. One place it said that Satan
entered into Judas and another said
Satan uh uh
entered into uh uh
uh uh
uh went into Judas' mind and it it put
it in Judas put it in Judas' heart
to do what he had to do.
So now, the seven spirits was around her
influencing her. Yeah.
Not in her.
The
The Lord said, "I set before you life
and death, good and evil. Choose." And
if you choose evil, that's your choice.
Yeah. Didn't Paul tell the Galatians,
"Who have bewitched you?"
Mhm. That's right.
Yeah. They was
inside of nobody. What they do is
they uh uh uh uh
they influence you. Same thing with
Jesus. You see knock at the door.
Yeah. The door of your mind. If you open
up, I will come in to you and sup with
you. You know Jesus going to walk inside
of your head?
He through his word.
There you go.
That's right.
Mhm.
All right.
I hope that answered your question.
Okay. And I was going to just have uh
Julius repeat again that Satan
uh is called demons or devils or both.
And you added some more uh names. Yeah,
familiar spirits,
demons, fallen angels,
um
unclean spirits, unclean spirits, yes.
Unclean spirits.
Yeah.
Yeah. Who is talking about talked about
uh
persuading.
Remember the spirit
Ahab, how he got persuaded.
Yeah.
First Kings 22.
You read about that. He said, "I'm going
to send a lying spirit in the mouth of
all thy prophets." That's he persuaded.
That's right.
Yep.
All right, sister Deborah, time check.
The time is 9:01.
All right, we have ran out of time.
And we like to thank everybody from all
around the world who tuned in with us
this evening.
We took joy in partaking in your
questions. But we like to say if you
submitted one and we didn't get to it,
please don't resubmit it. Sister Deborah
will take it, put it in rotation, and we
will deal with that question next week.
So, until we all come together again,
please be safe, be blessed, stay prayed
up, and brother Tangel will close us
out.
Our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done in
earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread, and
forgive us of our debts, as we forgive
our debtors.
And lead us not into temptation, but
deliver us from evil. For thine is the
kingdom, and the power, and the glory
forever. In Jesus' name we pray.